### FRONT END DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER

Professional Profile

I'm a front end designer and developer originally from Ireland but currently living in Eureka, California. I've worked in the area of front end design following me graduation from college in 2006.

My approach to every project is to build functional and highly usable design while optimizing for mobile performance and page load time.

# Qualifications

- Design, Layout and Typography
- Cross-browser compatibility
- Mobile Web Design
- Interactive Prototypes
- WordPress Theme Design
- Google Analytics Certified

### Relevant Experience

Examples of my work can be viewed on my portfolio: <a href="http://dev14.net">http://dev14.net</a> Â

### Experience

Front End Designer and Developer Oct 2010 to Aug 2015 Ideal Positions  $i\frac{1}{4}$  City , STATE

- My current position is in the area of front end design and development for our client base at Ideal Positions.
- My role is primarily designing and developing new websites for existing advertising customers (Google Adwords).
- Many of our clients have very outdated websites and want to have more control over their online branding and content.
- My role consists of interfacing with the client from the very beginning of a project to signing off on it.
- This includes the initial meeting to gather requirements, proposing and discussing possible solutions and design drafts, content writing and editing and ultimately developing the solution.
- A list of my projects can be seen on my portfolio.

Front End Designer and Developer Aug 2008 to Aug 2009

WS Management i1/4 City, STATE

- Managed the design and development of several "white label" websites for the company.
- These front end designs interfaced with the companies API to provide content to the end users.

Front End Designer Sep 2006 to Aug 2008

Version 1 il/4 City, STATE

- At Version 1 I was part of the design and development team that word on several large projects for government state bodies.
- These included: Irish Health and Safety Authority Liaised between both the Business Analyst and Developers to ensure the functional
  requirements document was visually represented as a working prototype to present to the project investors and ultimately used in the
  development phase.
- Dublin City Council (DCC) Designed a web based application to mirror the functionality of the live system
- The designed front end was then used in the development of the project.
- Irish Health Research Board (HRB) Worked closely with the project Business Analyst and lead developer in several workshops with the client during the design phase to discuss areas such as the application logic required, UI requirements and graphic design elements.
- Expertise CSS and SASS based on the BEM methodology Javascript Angular, React and Jekyll PHP Responsive and Mobile First Design Typography Git WordPress Theme Development.

# Education

Msc , Computing (Multimedia and eLearning) 2010 Waterford Institute of Technology it/4 City , Ireland

Computing (Multimedia and eLearning)

Bsc, Information Technology 2006 Waterford Institute of Technology i1/4 City, Ireland

Information Technology

Affiliations

Google Analytics

Skills

CSS, Javascript, Mobile Design, Git and Unix Command Line, A/B Testing, Landing Page Optimization